# AANSA ISHTIAQ

Entrepreneur. Writer. Fashion Journalist

## CONTACT

+44 7492 669919

✓ aansa.aki@gmail.com

2 London, United Kingdom

www.linkedin.com/in/aansaishtiaq

medium.com/@aansakhan

### **KEY SKILLS**

- Legal Research
- Commercial and Residential Conveyancing
- Entrepreneurship
- Networking and Communication
- Data Analyst
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python and Database (SQL)
- Notion and Canva
- Creative & Content Writing
- Creative Direction (Fashion)

### **EDUCATION**

**Swansea University** 2017-2020 Bachelors of Law (Hons) LLB Grade 2:1

East Berkshire College 2015-2017

**ESF Sha Tin College** 2010-2015 GCSE

# QUALIFICATIONS & PERSONAL DEVELOPMENT

Lincoln College (Online) PRESENT

Level 2 Digital Marketing

Girls In Tech, Inc.

Leadership Training Programme

**LMF Network** 

Mentorship Programme

**Swansea University** 

Certificate in Enterprise Award

Just IT

Software Development

### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

A highly dedicated business owner with creative writing experience and a passion for fashion. Proficient in crafting memorable and intelligent articles that captures a unique perspective from a combined background in law and fashion. Demonstrates an ability to manage multiple projects simultaneously, possess a strong attention to detail, and a remarkable ability to project empathy through writing.

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## FREELANCE WRITER

#### Medium

FEB 2024 - PRESENT

- Blending my legal career experience with my love for style to explore the complex dynamics of the fashion industry.
- Researching the digital world with a critical eye by observing the intersections of fashion, law, and culture.
- Brainstorming articles and researching legal implications of current fashion trends

# ECOMMERCE BUSINESS OWNER

#### aansa.khan

MAY 2023 - PRESENT

- Successfully founded and maintaining an e-commerce retail store.
- Responsible for sourcing, testing and marketing strategies to sell online and regularly communicated with customers and manufacturers.
- Curating campaigns for ecommerce products through ideation and SEO analysis.
- Consistently generating sales to keep inventory flowing and restocked units monthly.
- Managing finances, inventory and data using Microsoft Office.

#### PARALEGAL

**PRESENT** 

#### Maher & Co Solicitors

NOV 2021 - March 2023

- Expert in leading law software LEAP
- Leading the post completion team (SDLT submissions, AP1 forms, completion statements and billing, management company duties)
- Assisting solicitors in all aspects of commercial and residential conveyancing including drafting legal documents, lodging with Companies House and working with mortgage lenders.
- Office administrative duties including liaising with clients and legal professionals.
- Managing and completing live transfer, remortgage and sale files.

# AANSA ISHTIAQ

Entrepreneur. Writer. Fashion Journalist

# VOLUNTEERING

### Swansea University Law Clinic

OCT 2019 - APR 2020

# VICE CHAIRMAN OF LAW CLINIC FUNDRAISING COMMITTEE

- Leading committee to raise money for law clinic
- Raising awareness of law clinic to expand clientele base networking through social media and pitching proposals to local businesses.
- Increase financial contributions by organising student events and cultivating leadership skills.

### **VOLUNTEER**

- Amicus is a small charity that provides legal representation for those facing the death penalty in the U.S.
- Analysing information in order to perfect the legal database of people facing death row through data analysis.

#### **Christian Action**

JAN 2012 - JUNE 2015

#### VOLUNTEER

- Christian Action is an organisation that strives to improve the lives of people in the community through various vocational work as well as providing activities for minorities.
- Organising activities such as fundraising and event planning to providing assistance during many charitable exploits for social service initiatives.
- Teaching hard work and enphasising the commitment to supporting vulnerable disadvantaged individuals.

# WORK EXPERIENCE

#### LEGAL INTERN

# **Law Gate Solicitors**

OCT 2020

- Work experience in a general practice firm specialising in family law, immigration, and judicial review cases
- Implementing an efficient system of cataloguing cases to increase productivity in reviewing judicial review.
- Creating excellent rapport within the company for meticulous attention to detail when reading case files for errors and utilising Excel to categorise spreadsheets of database.

#### STUDENT ADVISOR

## **Swansea University Law Clinic**

OCT 2019 - FEB 2020

- Student advisor as part of the Clinical Legal Education module, advising clients pro bono in the law clinic with egal issues such as housing and commercial law.
- Communicating with clients through interviews and researching various alternative dispute methods to collate in an advice letter for each client
- Showcasing intuitiveness and excellent rapport with clients making them feel 'relieved and satisfied' in a stressful situation.
- An aptitude for legal research of what is in client's best interest by outlining all possible options for each client's situation, commended by the Clinic's Director.

#### SALES ASSOCIATE

### H. Samuel

NOV 2019 - JAN 2020

- Developing an ability for giving clients the best possible experience in a timely fashion with particular care towards each unique demand creating recurring clients who valued my assistance.
- Establishing a record of success in a high volume and pressured environment by improving performance through setting future goals and exceeding target sales continuously.

#### OFFICE ADMINISTRATOR

# **Juvenile Traders Limited**

**JUNE 2013 -SEP 2017** 

- Assisting in reviewing contractual agreements based on client needs and understanding the complexities of international law, gaining insight into business functionality and the relevance of corporate law in daily operations.
- Planning and coordinating meetings between venders and clients along with taking minutes of meetings; assembling, revising all relevant and necessary contractual material before meetings.